Jianghao WANG

Ph.D. Associate Professor

Room 1431, 11A Datun Rd. 100101, Chaoyang, Beijing People's Republic of China **☎** +86 (010) 6488 8842 FAX +3 (456) 789 012 ⋈ wang jh@lreis.ac.cn

Last update: March 1, 2019

Affiliations

Vocational

2018–now **Associate Professor**, Beijing, China.

State Key Laboratory of Resources & Environmental Information System.

Institute of Geographic Sciences & Natural Resources Research,

Chinese Academy of Sciences

2015–2017 Assistant Professor, Beijing, China.

State Key Laboratory of Resources & Environmental Information System,

Institute of Geographic Sciences & Natural Resources Research,

Chinese Academy of Sciences

2016–now **Associate Professor**, Beijing, China.

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences

Miscellaneous

2017-now **Research Affiliate**, Cambridge MA, US.

China Future City Lab, Massachusetts Institute of Technology: http://cfclab.mit.edu

2013-now **Associate Directors**, Beijing, China.

Beijing City Lab: https://www.beijingcitylab.com/

2012.09–11 **Visiting Scholar**, Wageningen, the Netherlands.

Department of Soil Geography and Landscape & ISRIC - World Soil Information, Wageningen University

Education

2010–2014 Ph.D, Institute of Geographic Sciences & Natural Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.

2007–2010 M.Sc, Institute of Geographic Sciences & Natural Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.

2003–2007 B.Sc, Hohai University, Nanjing, China.

Association Membership

committee Urban Big Data Special Committee, Chinese Society for Urban Studies member

secretary Resources Mapping Special Committee, China Society of Natural Resources

general

member	The Geographical Society of China
member	China Computer Society
	Teaching Experience
2016–2018	Modern Cartography – Web Cartography, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences. undergraduates, 30–40 students, 6 class hours
2016–2017	Geographical Information Science Tutorial and Practice , <i>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences</i> . undergraduates, 200 students, 20 class hours
2016	Map Design and Making – Geo-spatial Big Data Mapping, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences. undergraduates, 20–30 students, 3 class hours, Invited by Prof. Yingjie Wang
2016	Spatio-temporal Big Data Analysis and Visualization, <i>Tsinghua University</i> . undergraduates, 100 students, 4 class hours, Invited by Prof. Ying Long
	Awards and Honors
2015	Young Scholar Nomination Paper Award, The 4th International Workshop on Regional, Urban and Spatial Economics in China
2015	Outstanding Graduates of IGSNRR, Chinese Academy of Sciences
2013, 2014	"three-good students" award of Chinese Academy of Sciences
2012	National Scholarship for Ph.D
2011, 2012	"three-good students" award of Chinese Academy of Sciences
2010	Outstanding Graduates of Chinese Academy of Sciences
2008, 2009	"three-good students" award of Chinese Academy of Sciences
	Skills and Expertise
Major	Urban Studies and Planning, Spatial Statistics, Environments
Basic	Linux, MacOS, Windows, R, Python, SQL, C++, Shell, Javascript, HTML, LATEX Markdown, Github
Expertise	OSGeo, ArcGIS, GDAL/OGR, SAGA, GRASS, STATA, Mapbox, CartoDB, Web Map, Cloud Computation
	Languages
	Chinese mother tongue
	English first foreign language

member American Association of Geographers (AAG)

Research Projects

Principle-Investigator

- 2018-2019 **Novel Measures of Air Pollution's Social Costs in China: Big Data Analysis**, *MISTI Global Seed Funds*, Co-PI with Prof Siqi Zheng @ MIT CFC Lab.
- 2017–2019 Research on space-time geostatistical model-based ecological environment monitoring network optimization, *The National Natural Science Foundation of China*, (No. 41601427).
- 2016–2020 Key Theory and Method for Validation of Land Surface Remote Sensing Products Project 1: Theory and Methods, The Key Program of the National Natural Science Foundation of China, (No. 41531174).
- 2016–2017 Research on Human Mobility Pattern in Multiple Spatial Scales Through Geotagged Social Media Network, Open Research Fund Program of Shenzhen Key Laboratory of Spatial Smart Sensing and Services, Shenzhen University.
- 2015–2017 **Geographic Knowledge Integrated Spatio-Temporal Mapping**, *LREIS*, *Chinese Academy of Sciences*.

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-Reviewed Journal Articles

Forthcoming

Zheng, S., Zhang, X., Sun, , & Wang, J.H. The effect of a new subway line on local air quality: A case study in Changsha, Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trd.2017.10.004

Zhang, W., Derudder, B., Wang, J.H. & Witlox, F. (2019). An Analysis of the Determinants of the Multiplex Urban Networks in the Yangtze River Delta, Tijdschrift voor economische en sociale geografie, https://doi.org/10.1111/tesg.12361

2019

Zheng, S., **Wang, J.H.** [co-first leading author], Sun, C., Zhang, X. & Kahn, M.E. (2019). Air pollution lowers Chinese urbanites' expressed happiness on social media, **Nature Human Behaviour**, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-018-0521-2

Long, Y., Wang, J.H. [co-first leading author], Wu, K. & Zhang, J. (2018). Population Exposure to Ambient PM2.5 at the Subdistrict Level in China, International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 15(12), 2683. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph15122683

Ma, T., Zhu, R., **Wang, J.H.**, Zhao, N., Pei, T., Du, Y., Zhou, C. & Chen, J. A proportional odds model of human mobility and migration patterns. International Journal of Geographical Information Science, 33(1), 81-98. https://doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2018.1514608

2018

Wu, W., Wang, J.H.*, Dai, T. S., & Wang, X. (2018). The Geographical Legacies of Mountains: Impacts on Cultural Difference Landscapes, Annals of the Association of American Geographers, 108(1), 277-290. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/24694452.2017.1352481

- Jin, Y., Ge, Y.*, **Wang, J.H.***, Heuvelink, G. B. M., & Atkinson, P. Downscaling AMSR-2 Soil Moisture Data with Geographically Weighted Area-to-Area Regression Kriging, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 56(4), 2362-2376. http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2017.2778420
- Jin, Y., Ge, Y.*, **Wang, J.H.***, & Heuvelink, G. B. M. (2018). Deriving temporally continuous soil moisture estimations at fine resolution by downscaling remotely sensed product, International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation, 68, 8-19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2018.01.010
- Jin, Y., Ge, Y.*, **Wang, J.H.***, Heuvelink, G.B.M., & Wang, L. (2018). Geographically Weighted Area-to-Point Regression Kriging for Spatial Downscaling in Remote Sensing. Remote Sensing, 10(4), 579. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs10040579
- Zhang, W., Derudder, B., **Wang, J.H.***, Shen, W. (2018). Regionalisation in the Yangtze River Delta (China) from the perspective of inter-city daily mobility. Regional Studies, 52(4), 528-541. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00343404.2017.1334878
- Cai, B., Li, W., Dhakal, S., & Wang, J.H. (2018). Source data supported high resolution carbon emissions inventory for urban areas of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region: Spatial patterns, decomposition and policy implications, Journal of Environmental Management, 206, 786-799. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2017.11.038
- Li, X., Liu, S., Li, H., Ma, Y., **Wang, J.H.**, Zhang, Y., et al. (2018). Intercomparison of six upscaling evapotranspiration methods: From site to the satellite pixel. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres, 123. https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD028422
- Jia, Y., Ge, Y., Ling, F., Guo, X., **Wang, J.H.**, Wang, L., Chen, Y. & Li, X. (2018). Urban Land Use Mapping by Combining Remote Sensing Imagery and Mobile Phone Positioning Data, Remote Sensing, 10(3), 446. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs10030446
- Lei, C., Zhang, A., Qi, Q., Su, H., & Wang, J.H. (2018). Spatial-Temporal Analysis of Human Dynamics on Urban Land Use Patterns Using Social Media Data by Gender, ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information, 7(9), 358. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi7090358

2017

Wu, W. & Wang, J.H.*. (2017). Gentrification Effects of China's Urban Village Renewals, Urban Studies, 54(1), 214-229. http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0042098016631905

2016

Wang, J.H., Deng, Y., Song C., & Tian D. (2016). Measuring time accessibility and its spatial characteristics in the urban areas of Beijing. Journal of Geographical Sciences, 26(12), 1754-1768. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11442-016-1356-2

- Wu, W., Wang, J.H.*, & Dai, T. S. (2016). The Geography of Cultural Ties and Human Mobility: Big Data in Urban Contexts, Annals of the Association of American Geographers, 106(3), 612-630. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00045608.2015.1121804
- Li Z., Wang, J.H. [co-first leading author], Tang, H., Huang, C., Yang, F., Chen, B., Wang, X., Xin, X., Ge, Y. (2016). Predicting Grassland Leaf Area Index in the Meadow Steppes of Northern China: A Comparative Study of Regression Approaches and Hybrid Geostatistical Methods. Remote Sensing, 8(8), 632. http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs8080632
- Zhang, W., Derudder, B., **Wang, J.H.**, Shen, W & Witlox, F. (2016). Using Location-Based Social Media to Chart the Patterns of People Moving between Cities: The Case of Weibo-Users in the Yangtze River Delta. Journal of Urban Technology, 23(3), 91-111. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10630732.2016.1177259
- Zheng, S., Hu, X., **Wang J. H.**, & Wang, R. (2016). Subways near the subway: Rail transit and neighborhood catering businesses in Beijing, Transport Policy, 51, 81–92. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tranpol.2016.03.008
- Zhang, W. Y., Derudder, B., **Wang J. H.**, & Witlox, F. (2016). Approximating actual flows in physical infrastructure networks: the case of the Yangtze River Delta high-speed railway network, Bulletin of Geography. Social-Economic Series, 31, 145-160. http://dx.doi.org/10.1515/bog-2016-0010

2015

- **Wang, J.H.**, Ge, Y., Heuvelink, G. B. M., & Zhou, C. H. (2015). Upscaling in-situ soil moisture observation to pixel averages with space-time geostatistics. Remote Sensing, 7(9), 11372-11388. http://doi.org/10.3390/rs70911372
- Ge, Y., Wang, J.H., Heuvelink, G. B. M., Jin, R., Li, X., & Wang, J. F. (2015). Sampling design optimization of a wireless sensor network for monitoring ecohydrological processes in the Babao River basin, China. International Journal of Geographical Information Science, 29(1), 92-110. http://doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2014.948446
- Liu, X., & Wang J. H.*. (2015) The geography of Weibo. Environment and Planning A, 47(6), 1231-1234. http://doi.org/10.1177/0308518x15594912
- Hu, M. G., Wang, J.H., Ge, Y., Liu, M. X., Liu, S. M., Xu, Z. W., Xu, T. R. (2015). Scaling Flux Tower Observations of Sensible Heat Flux Using Weighted Area-to-Area Regression Kriging. Atmosphere, 6, 1032-1044. http://doi.org/10.3390/atmos6081032
- Wu, T. J., Ge, Y., **Wang, J.H.**, Stein, A., Song, Y. Z., Du, Y. Y., & Ma, J. H. (2015). A WTLS-based method for remote sensing imagery registration. IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 53(1), 102-116. http://doi.org/10.1109/Tgrs.2014.2318705
- Ge, Y., Liang, Y. Z., **Wang, J.H.**, Zhao, Q. Y., & Liu, S. M. (2015). Upscaling sensible heat fluxes with area-to-area regression kriging. IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters, 12(3), 656-660. http://doi.org/10.1109/Lgrs.2014.2355871

Liu, X.J., Song, Y., Wu, K., Wang, J.H., Li, D., & Long, Y. (2015). Understanding urban China with open data, Cities, 47, 53-61. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2015.03.006

Cai, B., Wang, J., Long, Y., Li, W., Liu, J., Ni, Z., Bo, X., Li, D., Wang, J.H., Chen, X.J., Gao, Q.X., Zhang, L. (2015) Evaluating the impact of odors from the 1955 landfills in China using a bottom-up approach. Journal of Environmental Management, 164, 206-214. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2015.09.009

2014

Wang, J.H., Ge, Y., Heuvelink, G. B. M., & Zhou, C. H. (2014). Spatial sampling design for estimating regional GPP with spatial heterogeneities. IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters, 11(2), 539-543. http://doi.org/10.1109/Lgrs.2013.2274453

Wang, J.H., Ge, Y., Song, Y. Z., & Li, X. (2014). A geostatistical approach to upscale soil moisture with unequal precision observations. IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters, 11(12), 2125-2129. http://doi.org/10.1109/Lgrs. 2014.2321429

Ge, Y., Avitabile, V., Heuvelink, G. B. M., **Wang, J.H.**, & Herold, M. (2014). Fusion of pan-tropical biomass maps using weighted averaging and regional calibration data. International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation, 31, 13-24. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2014.02.011

Kang, J., Li, X., Jin, R., Ge, Y., Wang, J. F., & Wang, J.H. (2014). Hybrid optimal design of the eco-hydrological wireless sensor network in the middle reach of the Heihe river basin, China. Sensors, 14(10), 19095-19114. http://doi.org/10.3390/S141019095

Ding, Y. L., Ge, Y., Hu, M. G., Wang, J. F., **Wang, J.H.**, Zheng, X. M., & Zhao, K. (2014). Comparison of spatial sampling strategies for ground sampling and validation of MODIS LAI products. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 35(20), 7230-7244. http://doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2014.967889

2012

Wang, J.H., Ge, Y., Heuvelink, G. B. M., Zhou, C. H., & Brus, D. (2012). Effect of the sampling design of ground control points on the geometric correction of remotely sensed imagery. International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation, 18, 91-100. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2012.01.001

Ge, Y., Wu, T. J., **Wang, J.H.**, Ma, J. H., & Du, Y. Y. (2012). Scaled total-least-squares-based registration for optical remote sensing imagery. Earth Science Informatics, 5(3-4), 137-152. http://doi.org/10.1007/s12145-012-0103-1

2011

Wang, L., Deng, Y., Liu, S. H., & Wang, J.H. (2011). Research on urban spheres of influence based on improved field model in central China. Journal of Geographical Sciences, 21(3), 489-502. http://doi.org/10.1007/s11442-011-0859-0

Deng, Y., Liu, S. H., Wang, L., Ma, H. Q., & Wang, J.H. (2010). Field modeling method for identifying urban sphere of influence: A case study on central China. Chinese Geographical Science, 20(4), 353-362. http://doi.org/10.1007/s11769-010-0408-2

Deng, Y., Liu, S. H., Zhang, W. T., Wang, L., & Wang, J.H. (2010). General multidimensional cloud model and its application on spatial clustering in Zhanjiang, Guangdong. Journal of Geographical Sciences, 20(5), 787-798. http://doi.org/10.1007/s11442-010-0811-8

Book Chapter

2017 Pei, T., Xu, J., Gong, J., Liu, X., Wang, J.H., Du, S., Qin, C., Yang, L. & Wan, Y. (2017). Spatial Analysis and Simulation. The Geographical Sciences During 1986—2015: From the Classics To the Frontiers (pp. 339-366). Singapore: Springer Singapore.

Working Paper

2016

Zhang, P., Wang, J.H. [co-first leading author] & Zhang, J.J., Can China Feed Itself under Climate Change? A High-Resolution Analysis. Social Science Research Network, (August 10, 2016), Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2821412.

Wu, W., Wang, J.H., Li, C., & Wang, M., The Geography of City Liveliness and Land Use Configurations: Evidence from Location-Based Big Data in Beijing. Spatial Economic Research Center (SERC) Discussion Paper 201, http://cep.lse.ac.uk/_new/publications/abstract.asp?index=5128

2014

Long, Y., Wang, J.H. [co-first leading author], Wu, K., Zhang, J.J., Population exposure to ambient PM2.5 at the subdistrict level in China. Available at SSRN. http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2486602.

Long, Y., Wu, K., **Wang, J.H.**, Shen, Z.J., Big models: From beijing to the whole China. http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.6417